

#### Oliver Nicolaas Ponder

<u>oliver.ponder@gmail.com</u> - please request address / phone if needed d.o.b: 02-11-1987
See a portfolio of projects at <a href="http://oliver.codes">http://oliver.codes</a>

27 year old Dutch / Brazilian. Currently writing Ruby at Memocom in Rotterdam, where he works full stack on applications and infrastructure. 3+ years of professional ruby experience.

Seeking further career and personal development.

Fluently Speaks: Dutch and English

Interests: Web Design, UX, Ruby on Rails / Chef / Configuration Management / Docker / Containers / Databases / Branding & Identity

# Experience

## **DEVELOPER, MEMOCOM – MAR 2011-PRESENT**

Maintains infrastructure, helps estimate and plan Ruby related projects. Stabilised a synchronisation procedure between a ruby application and Commence (A customisable database on Windows). Implemented Chef. Converted an application to a multi tenant architecture.

#### FREELANCER - PONDER DESIGN - AUG 2010- NOV 2013

Made custom websites. Taking time to understand the needs of clients and providing a good solution. Often worked with startups and people looking to take their already existing small/medium company online.

#### MARKETING OFFICER, ECONOMIC FACULTY ASSOCIATION ROTTERDAM - SEPT 2009- JUL 2010

Worked together in a team with 7 other capable students. Was responsible for the promotion of the association towards students, the university, companies, and international relations. Was also responsible for IT & further development and integration of EFR's online presence with it's CRM backend.

### **CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE - COOLBLUE - 2007-2008**

Provided technical support to customers of CoolBlue B.V. chain of web shops. Maintained a commercial approach while carefully listening to customer needs. Had to quickly adapt and learn to support new products. Showed rapid improvement and growth in sales and job efficiency.

## Education

# UNFINISHED ECONOMICS BACHELOR - ERASMUS UNIVERSITY ROTTERDAM

Completed first year, went on to do a full time board year at the faculty association and remained active in the student life. Found working on own freelance company more rewarding, and eventually resolved not to complete a higher education degree.

INTERNATIONAL BACCALAUREATE DIPLOMA - BRITISH SCHOOL OF RIO DE JANEIRO - 2006
Recognised internationally, the I.B. diploma met all prerequisites for the Economics study at Erasmus University.